# SIMON HONG

Longmont, CO 80501 303-941-6541 Email: simon\_hong1@yahoo.com

#### SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Sr. Quality Assurance Analyst with 10 years of software testing experience. I have blackbox and graybox testing experience. I have worked in Agile development environment performing system testing. I have tested both UI application and web based application.

#### ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Agile/Scrum development environment Front End/UI testing Functional Testing Regression testing Web Application testing Windows and Linux OS experience Integration testing Backend End testing SQL database knowledge Written test plans and test cases

#### CERTIFICATION

Javascript - NCSA 2018

#### **WORK HISTORY**

Oracle Inc. – November 2013 - September 2017 QA Analyst III

- Responsible for system testing archiving software. Performed functiona, integration, system and regression testing.
- Developed and excuted smoke tests on each candidate release.
- Experience executing and maintaining automated regressions test cases.
- Responsible for testing web-based application that interacts with archiving software using proprietary web services.
- Responsible for back-end data validation on Oracle and Postgres databases.
- Responsible for writing test cases based on User stories and acceptance criteria.
- Experience with JIRA and Rally for testing planning and bug tracking.
- Responsible for testing both Windows and Linux version of application.
- Responsible for release process for cumulative patches for the test group.
- Responsible for maintaining and troubleshooting my VM test environment including software installation, configuration and upgrades.

Reed Group August 2011 - Nov 2013 Software QA Engineer

- Experience testing desktop application and web application.
- Responsible for performing data validation on SQL Server database.
- Responsible for writing test cases based on design documents.
- Responsible to validating customer system after upgrades.
- Experience working in an Agile/Scrum development environment.
- Experience using TFS for bug tracking and task management.
- Experience with Visual Studio Test Manager for test case writing, management and reporting.

## Qwest Corporation October 2007 - August 2011 QA Engineer 2

- Experience testing call routing applications that use touchtone or speech recognition functionality.
- Experience testing applications web applications and back end databases.
- Successfully lead effort to get QA involved in testing applications that previously had
  no formal QA involvement. Determined when QA should get involved and working
  on test template for team to use for testing. Worked closely with QA Manager and
  Project Management.
- Experience writing test plans and test cases.
- Responsible smoke testing application after support upgraded client.

Intuit - Eclipse., Boulder, CO June 2000 – September 2007 Software Quality Assurance Engineer

- 7 years of Software testing experience in a real-time distribution management solution in a client-server environment. Performed end-to-end testing of order entry, accounting and inventory management.
- Responsible for running weekly automated regression suites in multiple accounts and analyzing result to be reported to Product Development.
- Responsible for defect tracking using a propriety bug tracking system that include subject area, recreate steps and solutions.
- Three years of experience in both writing test plans which includes high level coverage of areas that will be covered and writing test cases that include detailed test steps that are tied back to requirements.
- Working knowledge of the Product Development Lifecycle from a QA perspective.
   Been involved in projects from requirements gathering, design reviews, writing test plans and test cases including test case reviews, testing (feature and regression), and maintenance.
- Three years of experience using Mercury Quality Center as central repository for automated test results and creating reports project management.
- Assisting in the development of a tool that would bridge launch the automated test suite and upon completion of tests would import the results into Quality. Responsible to defining the requirements and beta testing.
- Responsible for maintaining automated test lab. Duties include making sure the test boxes had the correct software configuration and tools. Responsible for trouble shooting and diagnosing hardware and software issues.

### **EDUCATION**

- B.S. Computer Information Systems Columbia College
- B.S., Business Administration Major: Management University of Colorado, Boulder